翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
So Windows used to have a bunch of anime girl mascots
Windows曾经拥有一系列动漫少女形象作为其吉祥物
These anime girls are official Microsoft characters made by Microsoft to promote Microsoft software like Windows for example
这些动漫少女是由微软官方设计，旨在推广微软的产品，例如Windows
翻译自自动生成的英文字幕，使用AI工具，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
But the idea for these anime girl mascots
然而，这些吉祥物的创意并非源自微软，而是来自互联网
did not come from Microsoft that came from the internet
Microsoft did not start using mascots like this until Windows 7 in 2009
直到2009年，Windows 7才开始使用这样的吉祥物
But some of these characters have existed online since the early 2000s
但这些角色中自2000年代初就已经存在于网络上了
翻译质量权威评价：原来24年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
And they have a specific name they're called OS tan
它们有一个特定的名字，叫做“系统娘”
And if you watch anime you probably know what this means to some extent
如果你看动漫，你可能在某种程度上知道这意味着什么
But tan is supposed to be a cute childish way of saying Chan at the end of a name
但“tan”其实是“酱”的一种萌系、童趣化的说法
*日语后缀 -tan （たん），这是 -chan （ちゃん） 的过于可爱的错误发音
例如：欧尼酱(お兄ちゃん) o ni i chyan*
And I'm not going to be doing that the entire video so I'm calling them OS Chan from now on
我不会在整个视频里都这么叫，所以从现在开始我会称它们为“系统娘”
And these OS Chan started popping up in the early 2000s on image boards
这些系统娘在2000年代初开始在图片论坛上出现
such as 2chan and 4chan though mostly 2chan
比如2chan和4chan，不过主要是2chan
And most of the art of os Chan and general portrays them as like cutesy and dorky
大多数关于系统娘的艺术作品通常将它们描绘得可爱又呆萌
That's probably because people generally imagine these operating systems at least back in the day as trying their best
这可能是人们通常认为这些操作系统，至少在过去，是在尽力而为的 :(
And believe it or not at one point in time people used to like Windows. Okay
信不信由你，曾有一段时间人们是喜欢Windows的。好吧
that was a thing that people did but the first personifications of Windows are thought to be Windows me
那确实是人们曾经做过的事，但Windows的首次拟人化被认为是Windows Me
which was released in 2000 and then OS Chan's name was me chan
它于2000年发布，而这位系统娘的名字叫“米酱”
*HAF：我直接音译了*
Because it was called Windows me and that makes sense
因为它叫Windows Me，所以这个名字很合理
And really the best way to describe me chan is that me chan is a meme
描述米酱的最好方式就是，让米酱成为一个梗
She was just a really good character to appreciate windows at the time
她是一个既能体现当时Windows的优点，同时又能吐槽它缺点的绝佳角色，因为Windows确实如此
and also say it was bad at the same time cuz it was
Like people like the fact that Windows existed but it's still was like really difficult to work with
人们虽然认可Windows的存在，但它的使用体验依然让人头疼不已
And those earlier versions of Windows had a lot more charm than the current versions of Windows as you can probably imagine
早期的Windows版本比现在的Windows版本更有魅力，这一点你大概也能想象得到
the newer ones are like Corocramp and on top of that since operating systems
新版本一团糟，而且由于操作系统在当时还算是个新事物，人们对问题的容忍度也高得多
were generally a newer thing people were way more forgiving of problems
In general when the current version of Windows is Windows 11 and that version of Windows still has bugs from Windows 7 yet
总的来说，现在的Windows版本是Windows 11，但还存在一些从Windows 7时代遗留的bug
People are going to be a lot less charitable to your operating system
人们对你的操作系统可不会那么宽容了
People were also super excited about the internet in general because it was all very new
人们对互联网也感到非常激动，因为这一切都非常新鲜
And dialup internet was not uncommon then
那时候，拨号上网还很常见
and a lot of you probably don't even remember having dialup which you probably never actually had it
你们中的很多人可能甚至不记得拨号上网了，甚至可能从未真正体验过
So here's what it sounded like
拨号上网的声音是这样的
Your modem would make that sound whenever you connected to the internet
每当连接到互联网时，你的调制解调器都会发出那种声音
I never personally experien it because I am 24 but yeah it sounds awful
我本人没有经历过，因为我24岁，但听起来确实挺糟糕的
And that kind of internet was not uncommon when me chan was becoming popular to put the time period into perspective
在米酱开始流行的那段时间，那种联网方式还很常见，这样可以帮助你更好地理解那个时代
And fasting forward in 2005 this animation called troubled Windows blew up on image boards
回到2005年，一部名为《Troubled Windows》的动画在各大图片论坛上爆火
and then made its way to YouTube and gain a lot of popularity
随后，它传到了YouTube上，并获得了极高的人气
And when I say a lot of popularity I'm speaking relatively to image boards okay
当我说它获得了极高的人气时，是相对于图片论坛而言的
It didn't like blow up or anything but it seems like the original upload from 19 years ago is still online which is crazy to me
它并没有像病毒那样爆火传播，惊讶的是，19年前的原版上传至今仍然可看，这对我来说简直不可思议
With that video's popularity and OS chan in general someone at Microsoft eventually
随着那段视频的流行以及“系统娘”文化的兴起，微软内部有人
saw these popping up and decided to make an official anime girl mascot for Windows
注意到了这些现象，并决定为Windows打造一个官方动漫妹纸的形象作为吉祥物
Windows 7 Ultimate DSP Edition this copy of Windows was limited to 7,770 units probably because you know Windows 7
Windows 7 Ultimate DSP Edition，这个版本的Windows限量发行了7,770套，大概是因为，你知道的，Windows 7嘛
It was only sold in Japan. It included a special wallpaper and Soundset for Nanami Madobe
这个版本仅在日本销售，其中包含了特别设计的Nanami壁纸和音效集
And Nanami is the mascot for Windows 7 and her name basically is Windows 7 by the way little tidbit
Nanami是Windows 7的吉祥物，她的名字“窓辺ななみ”其实就是“Windows 7”的日文谐音，算是个有趣的小彩蛋
They also released an official character profile that shows Nanami was born April 6 1992, the release date of Windows 3.1
官方发布的角色档案显示，Nanami出生于1992年4月6日，也就是Windows 3.1的发布日期
And she lives in Tokyo and has 16 extended family members
她住在东京，并且有16位大家庭成员
Now besides all that about the character the actual operating system itself is interesting
除了关于角色的这些信息，操作系统本身也很有趣
Thankfully someone uploaded a one minute long video that shows all of the things that this version can do
幸好有人上传了一段一分钟的视频，展示了这个版本的所有功能
Which I'll also link down below but yeah you get a little anami on the right ear screen kind of like clippy
我也会在下面附上链接，你在屏幕的右上角看到一个小Nanami，有点像回形针的感觉
I think the most surprising part to me about this is the fact that there was so much work put into it
最让我惊讶的部分是，居然有这么多心血投入其中
And and there was only 7,770 copies that's it there was no more after that
而且总共只发行了7,770份，仅此而已，之后就没有再发行了
So it's really cool to see they went all out with designing this special edition because they didn't have to do it this well
所以看到他们全力以赴设计这个特别版真的很酷，因为他们其实没必要做得这么好
It's extremely well done especially since it's only a limited thing
它做得非常出色，尤其是考虑到它只是一个限量版
And I feel like it's just really cool to see because I feel like if they did this today it would be a lot worse
看到这个真的很酷，因为如果放在今天，他们可能不会做得这么好
It just be anime girl on the front cover and that's it but this version of Windows 7 had custom everything
现在可能就只是在封面上放个动漫妹纸就完事了，但这个版本的Windows 7却定制了所有细节
including a custom installed disc
连安装光盘都是专门定制的
There's also an advertisement using Nanami to promote Windows 7
还有一则广告用Nanami来宣传Windows 7
And honestly guys it's a really cool advertisement
讲真的，这则广告真的很酷
I really don't say that about ads very often I personally like the ad cuz they show you how to build your own computer in the ad
我平时很少这么夸广告，但我真的很喜欢这个广告，因为它在广告里教你怎么自己组装电脑
it's animated so well and this definitely does not absolve Microsoft of their sins of course
动画制作得非常精良，当然，这并不能赦免微软的过错
But it's nice to see that Microsoft used to care it shows they actually can
但看到微软曾经这么用心，还是挺让人感慨的，说明他们其实是有这个能力
There's also an anime short series of the Nanami working in an akih Habra store
还有一部关于Nanami在秋叶原商店工作的动漫短片系列
If you don't know akih Habra it's basically the wee capital of the world
如果你不知道秋叶原，它基本上就是宅文化的世界之都
There's lots of anime themed to everything from stores to cafes as well as Tech stuff
那里有很多以动漫为主题的店铺，从商店到咖啡馆，还有各种科技产品
So the location they pick for the short series makes a lot of sense
所以他们选择这个地方作为短片系列的背景非常合适
But for what I could find there was only three episodes of this show
但据我所知，这个系列只有三集
I don't know if there's some kind of story to these or if they're one-off shorts because none of them are in English
我不知道这些短片是否有连贯的故事线，还是只是独立的单集，因为它们都不是英文的
I honestly have no idea where these came from or where I could find the original Source
说实话，我也不知道这些短片的来源，或者在哪里能找到原始出处
Because there is none so I checked the comments to see if anyone said anything helpful
因为确实没有，我看了评论，是否有人提供了有用的信息
我想知道他们都说了什么
They're just as confused as me even the guy who uploaded the video doesn't know
他们和我一样困惑，甚至连上传视频的人也不知道
笑了，听不懂说的什么鸟语
从哪找到的？我在网上找不到有关这个动漫的信息
I'll link them down below if you want to go look at them but I can't find an English version so sorry about that
我会把链接放在下面，如果你想看看的话，但我找不到英文版本，所以很抱歉
That's pretty much all the exclusive content I could find for this version of Windows
这基本上是我能找到的关于这个版本Windows的所有独家内容了
Which is kind of a lot given this version of Windows only had about 8,000 units
考虑到这个版本的Windows只有大约8000份，这已经算是相当多的内容了
They really went all out with this character and that might be because it's Windows 7
他们在这个角色上下了很大功夫，可能因为这是Windows 7
Windows 7 by far was the best version of Windows to be released up until then
Windows 7无疑是当时为止最好的Windows版本
Windows XP was functional but ugly in Windows Vista was just pretty. That's it
Windows XP确实功能强大但外观略显粗糙，而Windows Vista则主要在外观上有所提升，仅此而已
Windows 7 in my opinion is still better than any modern version of Windows
Windows 7在我看来仍然比任何现代版本的Windows更好
It really was just the peak of operating systems because it was just Windows 11
它确实是操作系统的巅峰，因为它就是没有AI、Edge、漏洞或其他任何问题的Windows 11
without any AI or Edge or bugs or any other problem
For example all the old control panels you can still find on Windows 11, 8 and 10 are from Windows 7
例如，你在Windows 11、8和10上仍然能找到的所有旧控制面板都来自Windows 7
Even Microsoft seems to think it was the best version of Windows
甚至微软也认为这是最好的Windows版本
because it can't get rid of it and I mean in general a lot of these problems with Windows 10 and 11 were
因为它无法摆脱它，而且总的来说，Windows 10 和 11 的许多问题
introduced into 8 which I think is everyone's least favorite version of Windows
都是从 8 引入的，我认为这是大家最不喜欢的 Windows 版本
It's just the worst one it was designed for tablets and no one bought Windows tablets
它是最糟糕的一个，它是为平板电脑设计的，但没人买Windows平板
So it was just bad Windows no one liked it and then on top of that since it was built on top of Windows 7
没人喜欢糟糕的Windows，由于它建立在Windows 7之上
all the functionality was garbage it was just a bad operating system
它的所有功能都很糟糕，就是一个烂得没边的操作系统
But even though Windows 8 sucks they did make multiple DSP versions of Windows 8 with anime girl mascot
虽然Windows 8很烂，但他们确实做了好几个带动漫妹纸吉祥物的DSP版本
The first OS Chan is named Madobe U with this cover art and the second one is named Madobe I with this art
第一个OS娘叫“窗边优”（Madobe U），封面长这样，第二个叫“窗边爱”（Madobe I），封面长这样
There were 4,000 units sold with each character so 8,000 total so kind of like Pokémon
每个角色卖了4000份，总共8000份，有点像宝可梦
But there's two versions of each game and they were sold with a Microsoft wedge Mouse with a Windows 8 logo on it
但每个游戏有两个版本，还附带了一个带Windows 8标志的微软楔形鼠标
I looked this mouse up and it is probably the worst Mouse I have ever seen in my life
我看了一下这个鼠标，它可能是我这辈子见过的最糟糕的鼠标了
I don't know why they would pair this mouse with this operating system
我不明白为什么他们会把这款鼠标和这个操作系统搭配在一起
The type of person who would buy an anime girl version of Windows does not want this mouse
购买动漫妹纸版Windows的用户肯定不想要这鼠标
You know that my guess with this is they we're trying to get rid of stock because who would want this mouse
我猜他们是想清库存，因为谁会想要这款鼠标呢
This mouse like objectively sucks look at it
太抽象了，看看这鼠标
But in general the Windows 8 DSP versions had less bonus content than the Windows 7 DSP version
总的来说，Windows 8 DSP版本附带的额外内容比Windows 7 DSP版本要少
They had three theme pack wallpapers event sounds and some character voiceover
它们包含了三个主题包、壁纸、系统声音和一些角色配音
There was also two limited edition akih Habra editions with 444 units being sold each for 88 total
此外，还有两款限量版的秋叶原特别版，每款各售出444套，总共88套
But that is not the end of the Windows 8 version
但这还不是Windows 8版本的全部
There was also apparently a Windows 8 can Edition from Unicom with 2,888 units being made
Unicom还推出了一款Windows 8罐装版，限量生产2,888套
This one included a notepad t-shirt mouse pad pocket media case U and I Badges and a freeze blanket
包含了一个记事本、T恤、鼠标垫、游戏机收纳盒、U和I版徽章，以及一条雪花毛毯
But I really couldn't find anything super concrete about this at the time I was writing the script
但我在写解说时，确实找不到关于这个非常具体的资料
If that changes when I'm editing I'll let you know with like text or something
如果我在编辑时发现了新的信息，我会通过文字或其他方式通知你
视频做完了，没什么新发现
One of the most notable parts of these Windows 8 versions is that there's a Windows 8 music video title through the window
这些 Windows 8 版本中最引人注目的部分，是一个名为《Through the Window》的音乐视频
That was presented on the second day of the windows developer day in Japan conference
这是在日本的 Windows 开发者日会议第二天展示的
which is honestly a same thing to see at a Windows Microsoft conference
在微软的 Windows 会议上看到这样的内容，说实话并不意外
It looks like an anime intro and these characters had their own Twitter account
看起来像动漫片头曲，而且这些角色还有自己的 Twitter 账号
The profiles give you a really good idea of how old these accounts were because just look at Twitter
从这些账号的个人资料就能看出它们有多老了，看看 Twitter 就知道
It's so old pretty standard brand things to do
这么老的操作，确实是品牌营销的常规手段了
Overall out of these versions of Windows 8 there is definitely a winner and it is the can edition
总的来说，这些 Windows 8 版本中，确实有一个赢家，那就是罐装版
The can Edition just came with the most cool things
罐装版带来了最酷的东西
like the T-shirt notepad mouse pad pocket media case smartbook cleaning PC cleaner U and I Badges in a freeze blanket
比如 T 恤、记事本、鼠标垫、游戏机收纳盒、智能本、电脑清洁工具、U和I版徽章，还有雪花毛毯
That is definitely the best Edition and when it came to the wedge Mouse
这绝对是最棒的版本，不过搭配上楔形鼠标的时候
I really don't know why they did that
我想不明白他们为什么要这么做
They really should have just made some weed Mouse pan with like anime girl boobs on the front
他们真应该做一些带有动漫妹纸胸部图案的鼠标垫
The wedge Mouse just seems like a really weird pick
选择楔形鼠标是个非常奇怪的决定
which really just makes me think that Microsoft was trying to get rid of stock for this garbage Mouse
这让我不禁怀疑，微软是不是在清仓处理这款难用的鼠标
Because I just look at it it's bad it's a bad Mouse
因为它看起来就很糟糕，是个很差的鼠标
Microsoft definitely went all out for the advertising of Windows 8 not so much the effort Department
微软在Windows 8的广告宣传上下了很大功夫，但在实际产品上却没那么用心
There was a lot more versions of Windows 8 but a lot less cool things and unique things
Windows 8有很多版本，但真正酷炫和独特的东西却少了很多
That's probably just because at the time people thought of Windows 8 as being the future
这可能是因为当时人们认为Windows 8代表了未来
It wasn't cuz it sucks Microsoft was really trying to push twoin ones a lot and also like you know tablets a lot
不是因为它差劲，而是因为微软当时大力推广二合一设备和平板电脑
No one wanted either of those devices they just didn't and this was also around the same time as Windows phone
当时没人真正想要这些设备，而且那段时间也正好是Windows Phone的时期
Microsoft really thought they had something here but generally speaking no one wanted this version to window no one
微软以为自己抓住了未来的趋势，但现实是，没人想要这种版本的Windows
No one did usually people who use Windows 8 were forced to
通常使用Windows 8的人都是被迫的
like myself I and many others did not want my operating system to look like this
我和许多人一样，并不希望我的操作系统变成这个样子
This was stupid no one wanted this why did you even do it but thankfully even though Windows 8 sucked
这太愚蠢了，没人想要这个，你们为什么要这么做？不过幸好，尽管Windows 8很糟糕
Windows 8.1 also got an OS chan and Windows 8.1 was a lot better
Windows 8.1 也有了系统娘，而且 Windows 8.1 要好得多
The Windows 8.1 Pro DSP Edition is one of the best editions
Windows 8.1 Pro DSP 版是最出色的版本之一
We've seen so far this version is the Madobe family version by Windows plus
到目前为止，我们看到的是由 Windows plus 推出的 Madobe 家族版本
*HAF：听不清，原字幕也没有是谁推出的*
and was limited to 1,000 units this version came with the Madobe family picture wallpaper
并且限量发行 1000 套，此版本附带了 Madobe 家族图片壁纸
The Madobe character voices a complete edition
Madobe 角色配音的完整版，以及包含完整版 Windows 主题包，均与角色相关
and a complete edition Windows theme pack as far as bonuses related to characters
It also came with this Pasam Data Hikkoshi 9 plus license key
它还附带了 Pasam Data Hikkoshi 9 Plus 的许可证密钥
It seems to be some kind of data software for like stem fields which really Narrows down the Target
似乎是一款针对 STEM 领域的数据软件，这大大缩小了这个版本的目标用户群体，不是吗？
demographic for this version of Windows doesn't it
It also came with a 3-month free trial for Skype which no one really wanted
它还附带了一个为期三个月的 Skype 免费试用，但没人真正想要
It also came with the Microsoft sculpt Madobe Mouse which is an improvement over the wedge
它还附带了 Microsoft Sculpt Madobe 鼠标，相比楔形有所改进
But it's still kind of looks terrible and unlike other versions of Windows Pro DSP
但它看起来有些糟糕，而且与其他版本的 Windows Pro DSP 不同
This version was available for custom PCS from multiple companies
此版本可通过多家公司定制 PC 获得
These versions had different things they included two types of custom wallpapers
这些版本包含不同的内容，其中有两种自定义壁纸，以及一个包含系统语音的圣诞节和新年主题包
in a Christmas and new year's theme pack with system voices
Microsoft was definitely slowing down with these mascots around Windows 8.1
微软在 Windows 8.1 时期逐渐减少了这些吉祥物的使用
Because even though this version of Windows is called 8.1
即便这个版本的 Windows 被称为 8.1
it was more popular than Windows 8 because it fixed all of Windows 8's problems
它比 Windows 8 更受欢迎，因为它修复了 Windows 8 的所有问题
So the fact that Microsoft slowed down with the OS chan around Windows 8.1 release
微软在 Windows 8.1 发布时放慢了系统娘的使用节奏
It's pretty telling that Microsoft felt like these were a waste of resources and time
这很能说明微软认为这些是浪费资源和时间的
But the Windows 10 Chan is really interesting
但 Windows 10 的系统娘非常有趣
Because there's no special version of Windows 10
因为没有特别版本
They just made the character and gave her a weirdly detailed backstory
他们只是创造了这个角色，并赋予了她一个异常详细的背景故事
So her name is Touko meaning 10
她的名字是 Touko，意思是“10”
It was picked by a fan poll on Facebook to kind of date this already
这是在Facebook上通过粉丝投票选出的，算是给这个已经存在的东西定了个日期
According to her profile she's part of the Madobe family to the windows family the same family as all the other OS chan
根据她的个人资料，她属于Madobe家族，与Windows家族同属一个大家庭，就像所有其他系统娘成员一样
But Touko is 100 years from the future and likes online gaming and supporting her friends
但Touko来自未来的100年后，她喜欢在线游戏并支持她的朋友们
So basically she's a mercy mate but she's also an excellent student and loves expanding her knowledge on technology
基本上她是个乐于助人的伙伴，同时也是个优秀的学生，并且热爱扩展她在技术方面的知识
Her manager is a bit worried she's a bit spontaneous and she also enjoys cheering on people who are working hard and doing their best
她的经理有点担心她有些冲动，同时她也喜欢为那些努力工作、全力以赴的人加油打气
and then made me think of her just cheering on all those salary men in anime who look like corpses
这让我想到她在为那些看起来像行尸走肉动漫里的上班族们加油的样子
This might be a cultural divide thing but this character is like obnoxiously perfect to me
这可能是文化差异的问题，但对我来说，这个角色完美得有点让人讨厌
It's also weird they gave this character this much backstory when they didn't really use her in any kind of promotions at all
奇怪的是，他们为这个角色设定了这么多背景故事，却根本没有在任何宣传中使用她
like there's some things with Touko in it but not many and it's kind of weird given the fact that her backstory is so detailed
确实有一些关于Touko的内容，但并不多，考虑到她的背景故事如此详细，这确实有点奇怪
The Windows 7 character got way more attention to had a way less detailed backstory
Windows 7的角色得到了更多的关注，尽管她的背景故事远没有那么详细
The only thing I could find that's still up is a do it yourself series on YouTube on building computers
我唯一能找到的还在更新的内容是一个关于组装电脑的DIY系列，发布在YouTube上
which I think is officially endorsed because they all link to each other like it links to their official Twitter page
我认为这是官方认可的，因为它们都相互链接，比如它链接到了他们的官方Twitter页面
So I'm assuming it's official but this is the only official content I could find with Touko in it
我假设这是官方的，这是我唯一能找到的包含Touko的官方内容
I'm not saying others don't exist this is just all I could find though a lot of it is like nuked
我并不是说其他的不存在，这只是我能找到的所有内容，尽管很多内容都被删除了
I don't know why Microsoft did this whole thing where they nuked a bunch of stuff we'll go over a little bit more later
我不知道为什么微软会这样做，删了很多东西，我们稍后再详细讨论一下
but they nuked all this stuff and there was also an introduction video of Touko
他们删除了所有这些内容，而且原本还有一个Touko的介绍视频
which is removed and I can't find a re-upload anywhere
这个视频已经被删除了，我找不到重新上传的版本
like it might be out there somewhere but I am doubtful because I can't find it
也许它还在某个地方，但我对此表示怀疑，因为我找不到它
All the videos related to these characters are pretty under the radar
所有与这些角色相关的视频都相当低调，不太引人注目
but Touko did get a fair share of unofficial content made
不过，Touko确实得到了相当多的非官方创作内容
There's a custom Touko Windows 10 thing you can get
有一个自定义的Touko Windows 10主题可以下载
There's also a a custom OSU level based off of Touko
还有一个基于Touko的自定义OSU关卡
That is probably the least surprising thing about this character
这可能是关于这个角色最不令人惊讶的事情了
Honestly OSU and anime girls that's like the two things that go together the most
说实话，OSU和动漫女孩，这两者简直是绝配
But after Windows 10 released Microsoft basically killed off these mascots
但在Windows 10发布后，微软基本上就放弃了这些吉祥物
The company was making them got switched up to a VPN
负责制作这些吉祥物的公司被转去做VPN了
So there is no official OS Chan for Windows 11
所以Windows 11没有官方的角色
But there is a fan made one her name is Ichika Madobe and her name basically means Windows 11
但有一个粉丝创作的角色，她的名字叫窓辺一花（Ichika Madobe），基本上就是Windows 11的意思
Microsoft has never officially made this character Canon as we just discussed
正如我们刚才讨论的，微软从未正式将这个角色纳入官方设定
But Microsoft did mention this character in an Instagram reel
但微软确实在一个Instagram短视频中提到过这个角色
So they at least acknowledge a character exist officially cuz it's on their official account
所以他们至少在官方账号上承认了这个角色的存在
But the timeline of these characters in general is honestly pretty weird
但总的来说，这些角色的时间线相当奇怪
They released the windows 7 OS chan at a really good time
他们在非常好的时机发布了Windows 7的角色
If Microsoft just kept leaning into it
如果微软继续深入挖掘这一点
I think it would have done really well I didn't hear about this at all
我认为会非常成功，但我当时完全没听说过这件事
I think part of Microsoft was like ashamed of the mascot because really they didn't push it that hard at all
我觉得微软内部可能对这些吉祥物有些羞于启齿，因为他们没有大力推广
But it is hard to gauge how well these characters did in Japan and other countries
但很难衡量这些角色在日本和其他国家的受欢迎程度
Because there really isn't many views on all of these videos
因为这些视频的浏览量都不高
But it's also all in Japanese with no translation
它们也全都是日语的，没有翻译
So it's pretty hard to gauge how popular it is in Japan
所以很难判断它在日本有多受欢迎
Because even me trying to find stuff on YouTube for these characters is pretty America Centric
因为即使我在YouTube上搜索这些角色的内容，结果也大多是以美国为中心的
Because remember the OS chan off on 2chan a Japanese image board
别忘了，系统娘角色最初是出现在2chan这个日本图像论坛上的
So to accurately find these characters and find out how popular they were
所以要准确找到这些角色并了解它们的受欢迎程度
I'd hit to speak Japanese which I can't do
我得会说日语才行，但我不会
But I think it's fair to say among the terminally online
但我认为可以公平地说，在那些极度依赖网络的人群中
These will remain very popular for a very long time
这些角色在很长一段时间内都会非常受欢迎
Because they were created by the terminally online
因为它们是由那些极度依赖网络的人创造的
The relatively short list of Os chan we just went over
我们刚才讨论的系统娘角色列表相对较短
It's really just the timeline of them going from unofficial to official
这实际上只是它们从非官方到官方的时间线
If you dig a Little Deeper the whole list of OS chan expands quite a bit
如果你稍微深入挖掘一下，整个系统娘角色的列表会增加得相当多
There is pretty much an OS chan for every operating system ever
几乎每个操作系统都有一个对应的系统娘
Starting at Windows 1.0 we have Windows 1.0 Chan
从Windows 1.0开始，我们有Windows 1.0娘
The names weren't really there yet
那时候名字还没有真正确定
But this OS would making as slow and innocent to personify Windows 1.0
但这个系统娘被塑造得天真，拟人化Windows 1.0
This character really is just like lobotomized
这个角色真的就像被切除了前额叶一样
That's kind of their whole personality that's really it
这就是她们的全部个性，仅此而已
Next we have Windows 2.0 Chan who personifies Windows change to graphical interfaces
接下来是Windows 2.0娘，她拟人化了Windows向图形界面的转变
Because Windows 1.0 definitely was not that usable
因为Windows 1.0不太好用
Maybe someone who actually used it would disagree with me
也许真正用过的人会不同意我的看法
But if someone born in 2000 Windows 1.0 looks like alien technology to me
但如果是一个2000年出生的人，Windows 1.0对我来说就像外星科技一样
Windows 2.0 is not much better but at least I vaguely understand the layout of this operating system unlike Windows 1.0
Windows 2.0也好不到哪里去，但至少我大概看懂这个界面，不像Windows 1.0那样完全摸不着头脑
Windows 2.0 Chan is the donor of windows 1.0 chan
Windows 2.0娘是Windows 1.0娘的升级版
She is supposed to be smart and extremely skilled unlike her mother Windows 1.0
她应该是聪明且技术娴熟的，不像她的“母亲”Windows 1.0那样
Next we have Windows 3.1 Chan and canonically she was close to Windows 1.0 and 2.0 in childhood
接下来是Windows 3.1娘，根据设定，她在童年时期与Windows 1.0和2.0关系密切
But doesn't remember much and for some reason they're never allowed to speak
但她记得的不多，而且出于某种原因，她们不能交流
When I say for some reason by the way it's like literally just some reason they don't actually say
顺便说一下，我说的“出于某种原因”实际上就是字面意思，他们并没有具体解释
A possible interpretation is that her memory was wiped or Windows 1.0 into Window chan were exiled
一种可能的解释是她的记忆被清除了，或者Windows 1.0和Windows 2.0娘被驱逐了
Really the most notable part of Windows 3.1 Chan is that
Windows 3.1娘最吸引人的部分是她还有一个对应的角色叫Windows 3.2娘，和她几乎一样，但会说中文，我觉得有点搞笑
She also has a counterpart called Windows 3.2 chan who is the same but speaks Simplified Chinese which I think is kind of funny
Next we have NT mama who is a depiction of Windows NT 3.x
接下来是NT妈妈，她是Windows NT 3.x的拟人化形象
As the name implies she's supposed to be a motherly figure
顾名思义，她应该是一个母亲般的角色
That makes sense given the operating system looking back at previous versions of windows
考虑到这个操作系统回顾了之前版本的Windows，这很合理
It's pretty obvious Windows NT is where they generally wanted to head with Windows
很明显，Windows NT是他们希望Windows发展的方向
Windows NT at the time would have been much better than any of the previous operating systems
在当时，Windows NT比之前的任何操作系统都要好得多
So a motherly depiction for this character makes sense
所以这个角色被描绘成母亲形象是合理的
Next we have 95 Chan which is definitely reflective of the rise of weebs in the late 90s and early 2000s
接下来是95娘，这无疑反映了90年代末和2000年代初宅文化的兴起
95 Chan is a depiction of Windows 95
95娘是Windows 95的拟人化形象
and is a traditional lady from early modern Japan the reason 95 chan is like this
她是一个来自日本近代早期的传统女性，像这样
Because Windows 95 is generally considered a massive improvement over Windows NT
因为Windows 95通常被认为是对Windows NT的巨大改进
But it still respects the roots of the previous operating system
但它仍然尊重了之前操作系统的根基
Hence the traditional Japanese woman thing she is also unfamiliar with USB devices
因此，她是一个传统的日本女性形象，而且她对USB设备也不熟悉
The internet which makes sense because at the time dialup was really your only option
还有互联网，这很合理，因为当时拨号上网几乎是唯一的选择
A lot of people didn't have it and also floppy disc were still in use at the time
很多人还没有互联网，而且当时软盘仍在使用
*保存手办*
Windows 95 actually got USB support later in its life
Windows 95实际上在后期才支持USB
It was generally considered Hit or Miss if your USB device would work or not
通常来说，你的USB设备能否正常工作是个碰运气的事
That is why 95 Chan is scared of them she doesn't know where they are
这就是为什么95娘对它们感到害怕，她不知道它们是什么
But there's also 95 OSR 2.1 Chan which is a mouth ball
但还有一个95 OSR 2.1娘，她是个话痨
She's super Niche lorewise and she's just an inventor
她在设定上非常小众，而且她是个发明家
That's like pretty much it and an even more Niche version of Windows 95 chan
差不多就是这样，她甚至比Windows 95娘还要小众
It's just a western 95 chance and honestly these two additions are just kind of schizophrenic
她只是一个西方版的95娘，说实话，这两个角色有点精神分裂的感觉
There's like no info on them and they're just there there's like that's it
关于她们的信息很少，她们就只是存在，仅此而已
The next mascot is just a daong girl named in and she is just a dog girl that's it
下一个吉祥物只是一个名叫daong的狗娘，她就是个狗娘，仅此而已
It's not even for a specific operating system
她甚至不是为某个特定的操作系统设计的
It's just an extension of the family of Windows NT
她只是Windows NT家族的延伸
They have no specific traits besides being a dog girl that's it
除了是个狗娘之外，她们没有任何特定的特征，仅此而已
that's that's that's just character
这这这就只是这样
Next we have Windows 97 and 98 SE
接下来是Windows 97和98 SE
These characters are also lesser known and have less detail
这些角色也不太为人所知，细节也更少
But Windows 97 is a traditional Chinese girl and Windows 98 and 98 SE are school girls
但Windows 97是一个传统的中国女孩，而Windows 98和98 SE则是女学生
and guys I know the neck beard stereotype was a stereotype
我知道“宅男”是个刻板印象
But alls I'm saying is it didn't appear at a thin air
但我想说的是，这个印象并非凭空出现的
Okay and next we have the server chan
好的，接下来是Server 酱
which I'm covering all at the same time even though it's not really in order
虽然顺序不太对，但我会一次性介绍所有的Server 酱
Because within this universe of OS chan they are definitely Side characters
因为在这个系统娘的宇宙中，她们绝对是配角
First we have the 2003 server and she is half girl half fish for some reason
首先是2003 Server，她是个半人半鱼的女孩，原因不明
The bunnet on her head is an ethernet hub
她头上的帽子是交换机
Because servers have big ethernet hubs
因为服务器有大型的交换机
Besides that there is not much of this character
除此之外，这个角色没有太多其他特点
It's just just a personified server so people could make memes about the stuff they like
她只是一个人形化的服务器，方便人们制作他们喜欢的梗图
But after someone made Windows 2003 chan
但在有人创造了Windows 2003娘之后
People went back and made a Windows 2000 Chan
人们又回过头来创造了Windows 2000娘
Then later made a Windows 2008 Chan
后来又创造了Windows 2008娘
The blonde one is 2008 and the blue hair one is 2000 and the pink hair one is 2003
金发的是2008，蓝发的是2000，粉发的是2003
Next we have Windows XP
接下来是Windows XP
Windows XP Chan was depicted as a character
Windows XP角色被描绘成一个（很大？）的角色
*HAF：听不清，原字幕没有*
Because Windows XP was considered to be garbage blow at the time that looked pretty
因为Windows XP在当时被认为是漂亮的垃圾
I actually did not know XP had this reputation of being trash when it first released
我不知道XP刚发布时有这种“垃圾”的名声
Because everyone who talks about XP now just says it's better than Vista
因为现在谈论XP的人都说它比Vista好
That's pretty much it but my assumption was wrong it was bad when it launched and they fixed it over time
差不多就是这样，但我的假设是错的，它刚发布时确实不好，后来他们逐渐修复了它
One of the reasons why the perception was bad at launch and it changed over time was because Hardware got better
人们对它的看法在发布时不好，但后来有所改变，原因之一是硬件变得更好了
Because Windows XP was a pretty demanding operating system
因为Windows XP是一个对硬件要求较高的操作系统
So having better Hardware helped a lot and then the thing that changed Windows XP reputation the most
所以硬件升级的帮助很大，而真正改变Windows XP名声的是Windows Vista的发布，因为它糟糕得多
was Windows Vista releasing because it was so much worse
I have personally used Windows Vista and it's a bad operating system
我个人用过Windows Vista，它确实是个糟糕的操作系统
It just is my experience is laggy and choppy and just bad
我的体验就是卡顿、不流畅，总之很糟糕
But for some reason some people like Windows Vista
但出于某种原因，有些人喜欢Windows Vista
I don't know why I hated it
我不知道为什么，反正我讨厌它
A lot of people I know hated it but some people did
我认识的很多人都讨厌它，但也有些人喜欢
The fact that Windows Vista his multiple OS chan is pretty self-evident controversial at the very least
Windows Vista有多个系统娘，这一事实本身就说明它是很有争议的
But the first two depictions are visbu and Vistake
前两个形象是Visbu和Vistake
which I hope I'm not pronouncing wrong but I'm making no guarantees bobu is a young ninja girl
希望我没念错，但我不保证，Bobu是一个年轻的忍者女孩
and Vistake is an older girl who wears a sailor fuku
而Vistake是一个穿着水手服的年长女孩
They're not related for what I can tell and they don't have any widely agreed upon lore
据我所知，她们没有关联，也没有广泛认可的设定
it's really just these designs that people would post
实际上，人们只是发布了这些设计
there's also this (?) version named (?) chan and yeah this is what replace xp's like (?) reputation this character
还有一个叫(?)的版本，是的，这个角色取代了XP(失败?)的名声
There's also a bunch of other minor versions of Windows Vista
还有一些其他次要版本的Windows Vista
But none of them were posted that frequently and the reason visto's identity
但它们发布得并不频繁，Vista的身份如此分裂，可能是因为如果你的电脑更好，它运行会好得多
is so split to people is probably just because if you had a better PC it ran much better
It still wasn't great okay and in defense to Microsoft
它仍然不算好，不过为微软辩护一下
They still haven't learned from this okay they're still doing the same thing
他们仍然没有从中吸取教训，他们还在做同样的事情
But circling back at the OS chan first up we have Windows CE
但回到系统娘，首先是Windows CE
Windows CE Chan is based off Windows embeded Compact which is an operating system for what looked like a Blackberry
Windows CE娘基于Windows Embedded Compact，这是一个为类似黑莓的设备设计的操作系统
Before the Blackberry really existed I had no idea this device existed
在黑莓真正出现之前，我完全不知道这种设备存在
honestly it's really cool it did because I did not expect this to exist in 1996
说实话，它的存在真的很酷，因为我没想到1996年就有这种东西
This device was way ahead of its time and taking inspiration from the device Windows CE chan
这个设备远远超前于它的时代，而Windows CE娘从它身上汲取了灵感
It's a fairy with a USB cable one
她是一个带着USB电缆的仙女
So like a fairy represents portability and the cable as a charger I am guessing
所以仙女代表便携性，而电缆可能是充电器，我猜
But there really isn't much art of this character probably because this device was so Niche
但这个角色的艺术作品真的不多，可能是因为这个设备太小众了
For our next character they're based off an unreleased version of Windows called Neptune
下一个角色基于一个未发布的Windows版本，叫做Neptune
If Microsoft did release this version of Windows the windows that released in 2000 would have been called
如果微软发布了这个版本，那么2000年发布的Windows可能会被称为家庭版，而不是Windows Me
The Home Edition instead of Windows me
Because Windows me is what they ended up releasing and if the Windows home edition of 2000 came out
他们最终发布的是Me，而如果2000年发布的是Windows家庭版而不是Me，互联网可能会大不相同
instead of Windows Me the internet might look drastically different
But when I can tell me chan shaped a good part of the internet
但据我所知，米酱在某种程度上塑造了互联网的一部分
I have no proof this character has done
我没有证据证明这个角色做了什么
But this character seems like it's a lot of inspiration for a lot of Internet
但这个角色似乎对互联网的许多方面都有很大启发
In general this is speculation based off things I've seen online you might be able to cooperate or disagree
总的来说，这是基于我在网上看到的东西的推测，你可以同意或不同意
But that's my take with it so I think if you swap Neptune for Windows me chan
但这是我的看法，所以我认为如果你用Neptune替换米酱
The internet would look a lot different especially since the os-tan Wikipedia page is based off of me chan
互联网可能会大不相同，尤其是因为os-tan的维基百科页面是基于米酱的
I imagine if me chan looked different it would have a huge butterfly effect
我想如果米酱看起来不同，会产生巨大的蝴蝶效应
But next we have an OS Chan that isn't really an OS Chan
但接下来是一个不完全是系统娘的角色
their name is silver light Chan and you're not going to guess this
她的名字是小光酱，你肯定猜不到
They're a personification of Microsoft silver light
她是微软Silver Light的拟人化形象
I know really different name a Microsoft silver light is some developer thing
我知道，名字很不一样，微软Silver Light是某种开发者工具
I'm honestly not sure what it is developers definitely know and they're definitely pissing me
说实话，我不太清楚它是什么，开发者肯定知道，而且他们肯定在嘲笑我
But so silver light chan was create with the explicit purpose of being an ad for silver light
但小光酱被明确地创造出来，作为Silver Light的广告
That also means we got an unhinged amount of detail about this character
这也意味着我们得到了关于这个角色的公开细节
First you started me put in promotions in Taiwan
她出现在台湾的推广活动中
Her popularity spread to other countries her blood type is B
她在其他国家越来越受欢迎，她的血型是B
She's a Libra she also likes singing dancing and music
她是天秤座，还喜欢唱歌、跳舞和音乐
In general and she hates spicy food
她讨厌辛辣食物
She also has three sisters who all have the same amount of insane detail
她还有三个姐妹，她们都有同样的细节设定
Honestly the weirdest part about this character to me at first
这个角色最让我觉得奇怪的部分是血型，因为我觉得这真的很奇怪
was seeing the blood type cuz I just felt like that was really strange
I felt like there was something I needed to know
我觉得有些东西我需要了解
But it turns out in a lot of cultures your blood type correlates to your star sign instead of your birth month
但事实证明，在许多文化中，血型与你的星座相关，而不是出生月份
So that's why it's listed here in for a lot of characters and vtubers
所以这就是为什么在很多角色和Vtuber中会列出这一点
In general which makes a lot more sense than people considering it a must no fact about themselves
这比人们认为它是关于自己的必备知识要合理得多
For our next OS chan we have Claudia Madobe we talked about her a little bit earlier
下一个系统娘是 Claudia Madobe，我们之前稍微提到过她
She's based off Windows Azure which is a cloud computing platform used to build applications and services and deploy them around the world
她基于Windows Azure，这是一个用于构建应用程序和服务并在全球部署的云计算平台
She is also an official Microsoft character so she has been in a lot of different commercials and advertising
她也是微软的官方角色，因此她出现在许多不同的广告和宣传中
In general she also an official Microsoft web comic
她也是微软官方网络漫画中的角色
But for some reason Microsoft pulled it down
但出于某种原因，微软把它下架了
原标题：The History of Windows Anime  原作者：spatnz
I don't know why I do know Navi plus that was doing these mascots got shut down though and replaced by a VPN company
我不知道为什么，但我知道负责这些吉祥物的Navi Plus被关闭了，取而代之的是一家VPN公司
原视频上传日期：2024年12月16日
But that's pretty much it so at least you know it existed at one point I guess
但差不多就是这样，所以至少你知道它曾经存在过
翻译质量权威评价：原来24年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！
But that has been pretty much all of the Windows OS chan
这几乎是所有的Windows 系统娘了
Subscribe if Follow Me Blue Sky down below and click check out all my content and have a good one
如果你喜欢，请前往油管订阅Blue Sky，查看他所有的内容，祝你好运！